

Murat Derin (PMP, ITIL Expert)

Project Management & Project, Software and Operation Teams Leadership

Phone :: (+90) 555 255 78 77 Email : <u>mt.derin@gmail.com</u>

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/muratderin/

Address : Istanbul

SUMMARY

I graduated from Istanbul Technical University(ITU) Computer Engineering in 1993. I did my master's degree in the same department between 94–98. Throughout my 30 years career I have developed my expertise in software development, infrastructure technologies and project management. I have accomplished many successful projects by working as both an expert and manager in companies in different sectors. I have successfully managed and completed many projects in the field of project management, which I have been active in the last 15 years of my career. I earned the project management PMP certificate in 2009, the ITIL expertise certificate in 2012, and the scrum master certificate in 2017. With different sector experiences, I have high business analysis skills, experience working in international companies and projects. I am willing to work in leadership positions in project management, IT software & operations teams in corporate companies, and I believe that I will be successful in these roles.

EXPERIENCE

Yves Rocher Türkiye – Project Consultant

Feb 2023 - June 2024

ERP Transformation Project (Project Leader as contracted consultant)

Sade Yazılım & Detera - Project Manager & Operation Director

August 2018 - June 2022

Anadolu Hayat Insurance Data Quality Project

Eureko Insurance Data Quality Project

Trade Minister , Fraud Detection Software System powered by AI (Sponsored by EU) $\,$

İşkur - Job & Job Seeker Matching System powered by AI (Sponsored by UNHCR)

Director Of Operation Team

IT Knowledge & Experience:

- Project Management-Waterfall/Agile +15 Year
- Strong Business Analyst +10 Years
- Infrastructure Technologies +15 Years
- Software Technologies +10 Years
- Process Development +5 Years
- SQL & Shell Programming +3 Years
- Data Analyst & AI Algorithms +3 Years
- Cloud, Web & Microservice Technologies

Sector Knowledge:

- Information Technology +25 Year
- Telecommunication GSM +18 Year
- Insurance +5 Year
- Public Sector +3 Year
- Retail ERP +1 Year
- Energy +1 Year

Management Skills:

- English (Professional)
- Ability to Lead Complex & Big Projects
- Strong Communication Skill
- Leadership Skill
- Comprehensive Analytical Thinking
- Solid Problem Solving Skill
- Decision Making Ability

Turk Telekom - Project Manager & Infrastructure Technologies Planning Manager

June 2009 - July 2018

Infrastructure Technologies Projects (Server Virtualization, Big Data, Storage, Cloud, Server Provisioning, Resource Planning) Business Project Finance, Billing, CRM IT Infrastructure Research & Development Manager

Turkcell – Infrastructure Technologies Expert

July 2000 - May 2009

Infrastructure Technologies Projects (Server Virtualization, Big Data, Storage, Cloud, Server Provisioning, Resource Planning, Data Centers, SAN, Data Consolidation, Configuration Management, Operation Standards Project)

Software AG -İş Analisti & Yazılım Geliştirme Uzmanı

May 1994 - March 1999

Emek Insurance System Project
Emek Insurance System Project
Toprak Insurance System Project
Nordstern İmtaş Insurance System Project

EDUCATION

İstanbul Technical University, Computer Science, Master

1994-1998

İstanbul Technical University, Computer Engineering, Bachelor

1989-1993

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

PMP - PMI 2009

ITIL Foundation - BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT 2014
Datacenter Architect - Data Center Dynamics 2014
ITIL Expert - BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT 2014
PSM I - Scrum.org 2017 PSPO I - Scrum.org 2017
SAS Viya Overview - SAS 2021
Applied Scrum in Project Management 2022
Devops Basics- 2024
Microservice , Web Based Software Development-2024
Cloud Technologies- 2024

HOBBIES

Sports , Basketball, Tennis, Football, Traveling in Nature and Cities, Following Technologies , Reading Books History & Science

(*) References available upon request.